Edson Arturo Rodríguez Govea

Colima, México (CST) LinkedIn Profile · GitHub

I am a web front-end developer mostly experienced with handling technologies like Vue.js and React.js who loves to learn something new and create simple and complex web pages for process and/or problem improvement.

EXPERIENCE

MAY. 2021 - NOV. 2021

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, HMH SISTEMAS.

Software company specialized in web development using React.js and Vue.js.

- Planned, designed, and developed 2+ software projects from zero to deploy using agile methodologies.
- Implemented reusable components in order to reduce the project development time.

Technologies implemented: HTML5, CSS, Sass, React.js, Vue.js (Options and Composition API), Buefy, Bootstrap, Gitlab, Git, i18n.

NOV. 2021 - JAN. 2022

FREEWAY COMPANY, MOBILE DEVELOPER

FreeWay is a startup company focused on the development of mobile applications for freight transport solutions.

• Participated in the creation of the first project coding the main structure of it.

Technologies implemented: Flutter, Graphql, Zeplin, GitHub, Git.

JAN. 2022 - NOV. 2021

FREEWAY COMPANY, MOBILE TEAM LEADER

Creation of a mobile application through the Scrum methodology where a team of new developers was trained.

• Helped to introduce new developers to the environment of the projects, creating solutions and managing a good internal code structure.

Technologies implemented: Flutter, Graphql, Zeplin, GitHub, Git.

NOV. 2021 - TO NOWDAYS

MID FRONTEND DEVELOPER, SONATAFY

Management and update of the customer administrative tools, based on automated tests and agile communications between systems.

- Improvement on the client administrative website both on usability and troubleshooting implementing automated tests.
- Contribution to a better planning for the data management architecture from the backend.

Technologies implemented: Vue.js, Jest, Cypress, Node.js, AWS, GraphQL, PostgresSQL, Git, GitHub.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023 - SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, SCHOOL OF TELEMATICS, UNIVERSITY OF COLIMA.

SKILLS

- Intermediate level developer.
- Front-end frameworks management.
- Feedback and support to arrive at the best possible solutions.
- Native Spanish language.
- English B2.

ABILITIES

- Commitment to teamwork.
- Willingness to learn.

SKILLS

- HTML5 3 years.
- CSS3 3 years.
- JavaScript, JS (ES6) 3 years.
- Git (Github, Gitlab) 3 years.
- Typescript 2 years.
- Vue.js (Vue 2, Vue3) 2 years and 6 months.
- React.js (Context API, Redux) 2 years and 6 months.
- Sass 2 years and 6 months.
- Bulma 2 years and 6 months.
- Scrum 2 year and 6 months.
- Flutter 1 year.
- Figma 1 year.
- Bootstrap 1 year.
- AWS (IAM, Lambda, S3, CloudWatch, Simple Queue Service) 1 year.
- NodeJS 1 year.
- GraphQL 1 year.

- Cypress 1 year.
- PostgreSQL 1 year.